in the conservative U.S. state I live in, Kansas.
في الولاية الأمريكية المحافظة التي أقطن فيها، كانساس.
I didn't follow along with the crowd.
لم أكن أتبع ما يفعله الجمهور.
I wasn't afraid to try weird clothing trends or hairstyles.
لم أكن خائفة من تجربة موضات ثياب أو قصات شعر غريبة.
I was outspoken and extremely social.
كنت صريحة واجتماعية جدًا.
Even these pictures and postcards of my London semester abroad 16 years ago
حتى أن هذه الصور والبطاقات البريدية من فصلي الدراسي في لندن قبل 16 عامًا
show that I obviously didn't care if I was perceived as weird or different.
تظهر بشكل واضح أنني لم أهتم فيما إذا تم اعتباري مختلفة أو غريبة أطوار.
(Laughter)
(َضحك)
But that same year I was in London, 16 years ago,
ولكن في تلك السنة، كنت في لندن، قبل 16 عامًا،
I realized something about myself that actually was somewhat unique,
أدركت شيئًا ما عن نفسي وهو ما كان شيئًا فريدًا حقًا،
and that changed everything.
وغيَّر كل شيء.
I became the opposite of who I thought I once was.
أصبحت عكس ما اعتقدت أنني كنت عليه.
I stayed in my room instead of socializing.
بقيت في غرفتي بدلًا من الاختلاط بالآخرين.
I stopped engaging in clubs and leadership activities.
توقفت عن المشاركة في النوادي والنشاطات القيادية.
I didn't want to stand out in the crowd anymore.
لم أعد أرغب بالتميز عن الجمهور.
I told myself it was because I was growing up and maturing,
أخبرت نفسي بأن ذلك بسبب أنني أصبحت أكبر وأعقل،
not that I was suddenly looking for acceptance.
ليس أنني فجأة كنت أبحث عن القبول.
I had always assumed I was immune to needing acceptance.
افترضت دائمًا أنني حصينة ضد الحاجة للقبول.
After all, I was a bit unconventional.
أخيرًا، أصبحت غير تقليدية بعض الشيء.
But I realize now
ولكنني أدرك الآن
that the moment I realized something was different about me
أن اللحظة التي أدركت فيها أن شيئًا ما مختلف بشأني
was the exact same moment that I began conforming and hiding.
كانت نفس اللحظة التي بدأت بموافقتها وتخبئتها.
Hiding is a progressive habit,
الاختباء عادة تقدمية،
and once you start hiding,
ويوم تبدأ بالاختباء،
it becomes harder and harder to step forward and speak out.
فإنه يصبح من الصعوبة أن تتقدم وترفع صوتك.
In fact, even now,
في الحقيقة، حتى الآن،
when I was talking to people about what this talk was about,
عندما كنت أتحدث مع الناس حول موضوع هذه المحادثة،
I made up a cover story
اختلقت قصة تغطية
and I even hid the truth about my TED Talk.
وحتى أنني أخفيت الحقيقة بشأن محادثة TED خاصتي.
So it is fitting and scary
إذًا إنه من المناسب والمخيف
that I have returned to this city 16 years later
أنني عدت إلى هذه المدينة بعد 16 سنة
and I have chosen this stage to finally stop hiding.
وقد اخترت هذه المنصة لكي أتوقف أخيرًا عن الاختباء.
What have I been hiding for 16 years?
ما الذي كنت أختبئ لأجله على مدار 16 عامًا؟
I am a lesbian.
أنا سحاقية.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرًا.
I've struggled to say those words,
كافحت لقول هذه الكلمات،
because I didn't want to be defined by them.
لأنني لم أرد أن يتم تعريفي من خلالها.
Every time I would think about coming out in the past,
في كل مرة أفكر بالخروج من الماضي،
I would think to myself, but I just want to be known as Morgana,
أفكر في نفسي، لكني أريد أن أكون معروفة بمرجانة،
uniquely Morgana,
مرجانة على نحو فريد،
but not "my lesbian friend Morgana," or "my gay coworker Morgana."
ولكن ليس "صديقتي السحاقية مرجانة" أو "زميلتي المثلية مرجانة".
Just Morgana.
فقط مرجانة.
For those of you from large metropolitan areas,
لأولئك منكم القادمين من التجمعات الحضرية الكبرى،
this may not seem like a big deal to you.
ربما لا يبدو هذا شيئًا كبيرًا بالنسبة لكم.
It may seem strange that I have suppressed the truth
ربما يبدو غريبًا أنني كتمت الحقيقة
and hidden this for so long.
وأخفيت هذا الأمر لمدة طويلة جدًا.
But I was paralyzed by my fear of not being accepted.
ولكن شلني الخوف من عدم القبول.
And I'm not alone, of course.
وأنا لست وحيدة، بالطبع.
A 2013 Deloitte study found that a surprisingly large number of people
وجدت دراسة أجرتها "ديلوت" عام 2013 أن عددًا كبيرًا من الناس على نحو مذهل
hide aspects of their identity.
قاموا بإخفاء جوانب من هويتهم.
Of all the employees they surveyed,
من بين كل الموظفين المستطلعة آرائهم،
61 percent reported changing an aspect of their behavior or their appearance
16% أبلغوا عن تغير في جانب من سلوكهم أو مظهرهم
in order to fit in at work.
حتى يجدوا لهم مكانًا في العمل.
Of all the gay, lesbian and bisexual employees,
ومن بين كل المثليين،
83 percent admitted to changing some aspects of themselves
83% اعترفوا بتغيير جوانب من أنفسهم
so they would not appear at work "too gay."
حتى يظهروا في العمل بأنهم "شواذ كثيرًا".
The study found that even in companies
وجدت الدراسة أنه حتى في شركات
with diversity policies and inclusion programs,
ذات سياسات تعددية وبرامج إدماج،
employees struggle to be themselves at work
يكافح الموظفون ليكونوا أنفسهم في العمل
because they believe conformity is critical
لأنهم يعتقدون أن مطابقة الغير مهمة
to their long-term career advancement.
لتعزيز عملهم طويل الأجل.
And while I was surprised that so many people just like me
وبينما كنت مندهشة بأن كثيرين مثلي
waste so much energy trying to hide themselves,
يهدرون كثيرًا من طاقتهم في محاولة إخفاء أنفسهم،
I was scared when I discovered that my silence
كنت خائفة عندما اكتشفت أن صمتي
has life-or-death consequences and long-term social repercussions.
له عواقب حياة أو موت وتداعيات اجتماعية على مدى طويل.
Twelve years:
إثنتا عشرة سنة:
the length by which life expectancy is shortened
الفترة التي تقلص بمقدارها متوسط العمر المتوقع
for gay, lesbian and bisexual people in highly anti-gay communities
للمثليين في المجتمعات المعادية للشذوذ الجنسي
compared to accepting communities.
مقارنة بالمجتمعات التي تقبلهم.
Twelve years reduced life expectancy.
انخفاض بمقدار 12 عام من متوسط العمر المتوقع.
When I read that in The Advocate magazine this year,
عندما أقرأ ذلك في مجلة "ذا آدفوكيت" هذا العام،
I realized I could no longer afford to keep silent.
أدرك بأنني لم أعد أستطيع التزام الصمت.
The effects of personal stress and social stigmas are a deadly combination.
إن آثار الضغط الشخصي والوصمة الاجتماعية مزيج فتاك.
The study found that gays in anti-gay communities
وجدت الدراسة أن لدى اللوطيين في المجتمعات المعادية للشذوذ الجنسي
had higher rates of heart disease, violence and suicide.
معدلات أعلى لأمراض القلب والعنف والانتحار.
What I once thought was simply a personal matter
ما اعتقدت مرة أنه ببساطة أمر شخصي،
I realized had a ripple effect
أدركت أن له آثارًا متتالية
that went into the workplace and out into the community
تغلغلت في مكان العمل وخرجت إلى المجتمع
for every story just like mine.
لكل قصة كقصتي.
My choice to hide and not share who I really am
إن اختياري لاخفاء وعدم مشاركة حقيقة شخصيتي
may have inadvertently contributed to this exact same environment
ربما قد ساهم بدون قصد في إنشاء هذه البيئة المتشابهة
and atmosphere of discrimination.
وهذا الجو من التمييز.
I'd always told myself there's no reason to share that I was gay,
دومًا أخبرت نفسي بأن ليس هناك داع لمشاركة أنني مثلية،
but the idea that my silence has social consequences
ولكن الفكرة بأن صمتى له عواقب اجتماعية
was really driven home this year when I missed an opportunity
عادت فعلًا هذه السنة عندما فقدت فرصة
to change the atmosphere of discrimination in my own home state of Kansas.
لإحداث تغيير في جو التمييز في مسقط رأسي ولاية كانساس.
In February, the Kansas House of Representatives brought up a bill for vote
في فبراير، طرح مجلس نواب كانساس مشروع قانون للتصويت
that would have essentially allowed businesses
يمكن أن يسمح بشكل جوهري لمؤسسات قطاع الأعمال
to use religious freedom as a reason to deny gays services.
باستخدام الحرية الدينية كسبب لرفض خدمات المثليين.
A former coworker and friend of mine
كان لعاملة سابقة وهي صديقة لي
has a father who serves in the Kansas House of Representatives.
أب يعمل في مجلس نواب كانساس.
He voted in favor of the bill,
صوَّت الأب لصالح مشروع القانون،
in favor of a law that would allow businesses to not serve me.
لصالح قانون سيسمح لمؤسسات قطاع الأعمال بعدم خدمتي.
How does my friend feel
كيف تشعر صديقتي تجاه
about lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer and questioning people?
المثليين والمتحولين جنسيًا والأشخاص الغريبين والمتشككين؟
How does her father feel?
كيف يشعر أبوها؟
I don't know, because I was never honest with them about who I am.
لا أعلم، لأنني لم أكن صادقة أبدًا معهم عن هويتي.
And that shakes me to the core.
وهذا يهزني من صميم قلبي.
What if I had told her my story years ago?
ماذا لو أخبرتها بقصتي قبل سنوات؟
Could she have told her father my experience?
هل كانت لتخبر أباها بتجربتي؟
Could I have ultimately helped change his vote?
هل كان لي أن أساعد في تغيير هذا التصويت بشكل كامل؟
I will never know,
لن أعلم أبدًا،
and that made me realize I had done nothing
وهذا جعلني أدرك أنني لم أفعل شيئًا
to try to make a difference.
لمحاولة إحداث تغيير.
How ironic that I work in human resources,
إنه أمر مثير للسخرية أنني أعمل في مجال الموارد البشرية،
a profession that works to welcome,
مهنة تعمل للترحيب
connect and encourage the development of employees,
وربط وتشجيع تنمية الموظفين،
a profession that advocates that the diversity of society
مهنة تدافع عن تلك التعددية في المجتمع
should be reflected in the workplace,
ينبغي أن تنعكس على مكان العمل،
and yet I have done nothing to advocate for diversity.
ولكنني لم أفعل شيئًا للدفاع عن التعددية.
When I came to this company one year ago,
عندما أتيت إلى هذه الشركة قبل سنة،
I thought to myself, this company has anti-discrimination policies
فكرت في نفسي، لهذه الشركة سياسات ضد التمييز
that protect gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender people.
تحمي المثليين والمتحولين جنسيًا.
Their commitment to diversity is evident through their global inclusion programs.
إن التزامهم بالتعددية واضح من خلال برامجهم للإدماج العالمي.
When I walk through the doors of this company, I will finally come out.
عندما أدخل من أبواب هذه الشركة، سأخرج في النهاية.
But I didn't.
ولكنني لم أفعل ذلك.
Instead of taking advantage of the opportunity,
بدلًا من استغلال هذه الفرصة،
I did nothing.
لم أفعل شيئًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
When I was looking through my London journal and scrapbook
عندما كنت أقرأ يومياتي وقصاصاتي من لندن
from my London semester abroad 16 years ago,
من فصلي هناك خارج البلاد قبل 16 سنة،
I came across this modified quote from Toni Morrison's book, "Paradise."
صادفت هذا الاقتباس اللطيف من كتاب طوني مورسين "بارادايس"،
"There are more scary things inside than outside."
"ثمة أشياء في الداخل أكثر إخافة من تلك التي في الخارج".
And then I wrote a note to myself at the bottom:
ثم كتبت ملاحظة لنفسي في أسفل الورقة:
"Remember this."
"تذكري هذا".
I'm sure I was trying to encourage myself to get out and explore London,
أنا متأكدة بأنني كنت أحاول تشجيع نفسي للخروج واستكشاف لندن،
but the message I missed was the need to start exploring and embracing myself.
ولكن الرسالة التي نسيتها كانت الحاجة إلى البدء باستكشاف واحتضان ذاتي.
What I didn't realize until all these years later
ما لم أفهمه إلا بعد مرور كل هذه السنوات التي تلت
is that the biggest obstacles I will ever have to overcome
هو أن أكبر المعضلات التي يجب عليّ التغلب عليها دائمًا
are my own fears and insecurities.
هي مخاوفي وشعوري بعدم الأمن.
I believe that by facing my fears inside, I will be able to change reality outside.
أعتقد بأنني من خلال مواجهة الخوف داخلي، سأكون قادرة على تغيير الواقع في الخارج.
I made a choice today
اتخذت قرارًا اليوم
to reveal a part of myself that I have hidden for too long.
بالإفصاح عن جزء من نفسي كنت قد خبئته لمدة طويلة جدًا.
I hope that this means I will never hide again,
آمل أن هذا يعني أنني لن أختبئ ثانية،
and I hope that by coming out today, I can do something to change the data
كما آمل أنني من خلال خروجي اليوم، أستطيع فِعل شيء ما لتغيير المعطيات
and also to help others who feel different be more themselves and more fulfilled
وأيضًا لمساعدة الآخرين الذين يشعرون بأنهم مختلفون ليصبحوا بطبيعتهم ومنجزين أكثر
in both their professional and personal lives.
على صعيد حياتهم المهنية والشخصية.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)